Guide to the Bert N. Corona Papers, 1923-1984
Department of Special Collections
- Subject files, 1923-1983, Series 10
  - CHICANO STUDIES MATERIALS, 1950s-1983, Sub-series 10.A
    - History of the Mexican People As Workers, Mr. Vasques, syllabus and outline, C.S. 444, Spring, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Immigration articles and clippings, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Immigration Course, Class material, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Immigration Course, Santa Barbara, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - International newsletters and flyers, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Journal Articles and other resource material, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Lessons in Mexican and Mexican-American history, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Los Angeles M.E.C.H.A. Newsletter, November 17, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - MECHA, California State Campuses, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Mexico/Southwest Collection, Chicano Newspaper Clippings, volume compiled by California State University Library, Fullerton, [includes several manuscripts], June 1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Narratives of North American Indian Captivities, Bibliography, N.Y.: Garland, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - National Association for Chicano Studies (NACS), program 8th Annual Conference, Houston, Texas, April 17-19, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - North Orange County Community College, Fullerton, Application for teaching credential, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - North Orange County Community College District, Fullerton, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Objectives of Chicano Studies, Chicano Studies Institute Position Paper, UCLA, June 1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Perfiles Mexicoamericanos: Biografías Bilingues Para Hoy, por Julian Nava y Michele Hall, Aardvark Media Inc., Walnut Creek, California, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Political Behavior, Chicano Studies 430, CSULA, Summer, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Reports of the Meetings of the Community Colleges' Board of Trustees, October 7, 1969-December 16, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - San Diego State College, Chicano Studies Materials, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Summary of Activities, Chicano Studies Research Center, UCLA, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Syllabus, examples of several different courses, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Teachers and Students, Report V: Mexican-American Education Study, Differences in Teacher Interactions with Mexican-American and Anglo Students, A Report of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Teatro Universitario en Español, program, December 6, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Term paper topics, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - University of California, Berkeley, Chicano Studies, 191, The Chicano and Mexican People as Immigrants, notes, syllabus, flyers, Spring, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - University of California, Berkeley, Course description, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - University of California, Los Angeles, Aztlan publications list, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Vazquez, Genaro, Su Vida y sus Costumbres, no author, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Environmental issues, 1973-1981, Sub-series 10.B
    - Colorado River Valley Salinity Plan, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Diablo Canyon Nuclear Power Plant blockade, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Ecology Center of Southern California, membership form, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Energy and Ethics: The Ethical Implications of Energy Production and Use, a study document issued by the National Council of Churches, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Environmental issues, ca. 1974 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Nuclear Power, clippings, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Santa Clarita Valley, California, clippings on toxic waste and the Center for Employment Training (CET), at Castaic Junction, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Seguridad de los Trabajadores Agricolas Durante el Uso de Pesticidas, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C., May 1975 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - La Seguridad en el Trabajo Como Elemento de la Salud Ocupacional Integral, by Enrique A. Velez, typescript, (13) pages, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Strip mining in Death Valley, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Substances that poison the workplace, information bulletins, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Immigration, 1967-1983, Sub-series 10.C
    - Alatorre, Soledad, Plight of Immigration Workers in the U.S.A., in New Perspectives, Journal of the World Peace Council, January 1976 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Analysis of alien eligibility Under Titles IV, XVI, and XIX, Social Security Act, 1974-1978 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Appropriations budget for the INS, FY 1978 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Arzube, Bishop Juan, talk on illegal aliens, March 7, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - The Bill of Rights and the Foreign Born, by Ira Gollobin, typescript, speech before the Immigration Conference of New York Lawyer's Guild, February 22, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Bracero Program, President Carter's H-2 proposal to import temporary farm labor from Mexico, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Bustamante, Jorge A., More on the Impact of the Undocumented Immigration from Mexico on the U.S.- Mexican Economies: Preliminary Findings and Suggestions for Bilateral Cooperation, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - California bills on immigration, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - California State Legislation on Immigrants, 1972, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Carta de Derechos Para Los Trabajadores Indocumentados, 1ra Conferencia Internacional Por Los Derechos Plenos de los Trabajadores Indocumentados, also in English, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Carter immigration program for undocumented workers, critique by Mark Day, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Carter proposal, analysis by Peter Schey, (draft) Carter's Immigration Package: A Windfall for Big Business, September 1977 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Carter's message on undocumented aliens, August 4, 1977,U.S. News & World Report, August 15, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Castillo, Lionel J. and the Department of Justice Statements, re: immigration laws, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Catholic Bishops, Testimony on H.R. 982, by Rev. Msgr. George G. Higgins, before the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship and International Law, U.S. House of Representatives, March 13, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Catholic Church and Immigration, clippings, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Catholic Church and Immigration, Conference: San Antonio, Texas, program and papers November 25, 26, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Center for Migration Studies, pamphlets, ca. 1971-1973, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Centro de Información y Estudios Migratorios, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Centro de Inmigración, articles of incorporation of the North American Center for the Study of Immigration Policy, 1978;grant proposals, correspondence, conference brochures, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Challenge for Nevada: Plight of the Undocumented Worker, Conference July 8-11, 1976, sponsored by Centre, The Centre of Development in Faith, Las Vegas, Nevada, text of presentation by Corona and agenda. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - The Characteristics and Role of Illegal Aliens in the U.S. Labor Market: An Exploratory Study, by David S. North and Marion F. Houstoun, for Linton & Company, Inc. Washington, D.C., (181) pages, March 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Charter of Rights for Immigrant Workers, statement, ca. 1975. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - The Chicano People as an Oppressed National Minority in the United States, no author, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Clippings and flyers, 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Comité Nacional de Organización Sindical de Trabajadores Inmigrantes, Pacoima, California, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - C.O.D.I.L. (Comité Obrero en Defensa de los Indocumentados en Lucha), 1977 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Communist Party Pamphlet, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Conferencia Nacional de Inmigración, Los Angeles, flyers, programs and memos, includes: Call to Action, and Convocatoria, immigration analysis, by National Coalition for fair Immigration Laws and Practices, and Una Historia de la Política de Inmigración de Los Estados Unidos de Norte América, Marzo 9-10, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Conferencia Nacional de Inmigración, Los Angeles, Report on the 1974 Conference, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Conferencia Sobre Inmigración, Commission on Social Justice, Archdiocese of San Francisco, Junio 12, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Court Order to stop deportation of Western Hemisphere immigrants, December 31, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Cranston, Alan clippings and correspondence on the Carter illegal alien plan, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Cranston Bill, Congressional Record, Washington, January 10, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Culiacan-Paros FIOACS, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Day, Mark, A Charter of Rights for Immigrant Workers, pamphlet, drafts and galley proofs, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Day, Mark, references for his article, A Charter of Rights for Immigrant Workers, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Decision on Right of Aliens to Police-like Jobs, clipping, February 5, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Derechos de indocumentados, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Los Desarraigados, a collective barrio communications project of La Raza in the Midwest, newsletters and flyers, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Dixon-Arnett Law, Section 2801 of the California Labor Code, papers and clippings on employment of aliens, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Eastland Bill, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Education Code re: undocumented pupils in California, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Eilberg Bill, (in Spanish and English), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Eilberg Bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act, June 24, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Employer Rights Under Immigration Laws, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Exodo Silencioso: La Emigración de Trabajadores Mexicanos a Estados Unidos, by Francisco Alba-Hernandez, xerox, 1946-1975, 1976? (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Five Year Restrictions for Newly Naturalized Citizens: A Constitutional Inquiry, by Jesus R. Romo, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Flyers and information from organizations working for fair treatment of immigrants and illegal residents, 1974-79 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Flyers and information from organizations working for fair treatment of immigrants and illegal residents, 1974-79 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Flyers on legislation relating to immigrants, ca. 1979 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Galindo, Genaro, Appeal Before the Board of Immigration Appeals, ca. 1974 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Greater Los Angeles Community Action Agency (GLACAAC), includes: Problems of Persons Without Immigration Documents in the Central Los Angeles Region, by United Way Region v. July 1975;County of Los Angeles Department of Public Social Services instructions on citizenship and alien age requirements, March 1976,. 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - H-2 Temporary Workers, Statement by Alan C. Nelson, INS to Department of Justice, U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Immigration and Refugee Policy, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Health benefits and undocumented residents, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Higgins, Msgr. George G., clippings from Texas Catholic Herald, 1978 Hispanic Taskforce on Undocumented Aliens, report, August 22, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Hispanic Taskforce on Undocumented Aliens, report, August 22, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - House Select Committee on Population, testimony, April 1978 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - The Illegal Alien Problem and Its Impact on Los Angeles Police Department Resources, briefing paper for staff officers Mini-retreat, L.A. Police Department, January 1977 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - An Illegal Alien's Right to Sue for Back Wages Under the Fair Labor Standards Act in Federal Courts, by Juan J. Hinojosa, MLAP, (7) pages, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Illegal Aliens, by Steve Ybarra, State Health and Welfare Agency position paper, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Illegal Aliens: Time to Call a Halt! by Leonard F. Chapman, Jr., Commissioner, U.S. Immigration and Naturalization Service, xerox from Reader's Digest, October 1976 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Immigrant Rights, flyers, articles, clippings, 1971-1981 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - The Immigrant Worker: His Right to Medi-Cal and Other Public Assistance Programs, by Juan Lopez, typescript, (27) pages, ca. 1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Immigrant Workers' Rights, Resolution 73 on immigration reform, 1977-79 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Immigration, Background Material, ca. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Immigration Bills, U.S. Congress, 1976, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Immigration Cases re: deportation, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Immigration Case re: exclusion of resident aliens from Juries, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Immigration, clippings on illegal aliens, 1972-1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Immigration Coalition of Southern California, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Immigration and deportation information from action groups, ca. 1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Immigration and Naturalization: General Information Laws and Visa Procedures, ca. 1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service, ca. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service announcement of survey of illegal aliens, Manpower Information Service, 1976? (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service, re: Federal law on arrest of aliens, August 13, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Services, Annie Gutierrez, District Director, to charges that the INS was using children as material witnesses against illegal immigrants, March 28, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Services, Officers' Guide to arrests, May 1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Immigration from Mexico and U.S. policy, clippings, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Immigration, International Institute, information and forms for immigration, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Immigration Issues, clippings and flyers, 1971-1975 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Immigration Laws and Visa Procedures, ca. 1977 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Immigration Laws, recent changes, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Immigration and Public Policy, Symposium, Houston, Texas, April 15-16, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Immigration Plan - for People or Profit? by Ed McCaughan and Peter Baird, NACLA-West, ca. 1977 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Immigration Policy in the U.S., includes a report on a conference in San Francisco, The Statue of Liberty: Should We Tear it Down?, 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Immigration - Why the Lady Still Beckons, by Phyllis Berman, Forbes, October 30, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Immigration Workshop, Chicago, program, April 16, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Indiana Bill on Illegal Aliens, proposed 1977 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Information on the Social and economic implications of illegal migrants in the U.S., ca. 1979 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Inmigración Entre Paises Socialistas, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - International Committee on Immigration and Public Policy, 1977-1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - International Ladies Garment Workers Union v. INS, 1976-1978re: raiding plants for illegal aliens (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Interpreter Releases, an information service on immigration and naturalization and related matters, December 14, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Jewelers Union, (Los Angeles?), 1977 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Kennedy Bill, amendment to immigration bill, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Kennedy, Senator Edward, Letter requesting support for political rights for Mexican and Latin American immigrants, October 8, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Labor for Immigrant Workers, flyers and news reports, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Labor Support for Aliens, flyers and news clippings, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Legal Aid Society on immigration policies, June 21, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Lesko Report, Basic Data and Guidance Required to Implement a Major Illegal Alien Study During Fiscal Year 1976, prepared for the Office of Planning and Evaluation, Immigration and Naturalization Service, October 15, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Los Angeles Bar Association, Report on Deportation and Removal of Aliens, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Los Angeles Coalition Packet, April 27, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Los Angeles Committee for the Defense of The Bill of Rights, flyer opposing Fred Firestone deportation, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Los Angeles Immigration Coalition flyer, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Los Angeles Times Proposal on Aliens, for 1979 Congress, November 21, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Loya, Yolanda et al. v. Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Lutheran National Conference, Illegal Aliens: Patterns and Policies, Los Angeles, June 28, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Manning, Cardinal Timothy Law, Los Angeles, on visas for those who are undocumented, September 16, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - The Media and Undocumented Migrants, talk by Susan Jacoby February 25, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Mexican migration to the United States, data and graphs, 1924-1977 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Migration Bulletin, No.2, (Intergovernmental Committee for European Migration, July 1978) (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - National Center for Immigrants' Rights, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - National Center for the Study of Aliens' Rights (NCSAR), Position Paper on Undocumented Aliens in the United States, presented to Attorney General Griffin Bell, May 12, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - National Chicano Moratorium Committee, clippings, petitions, (some with signatures), 1970;newsletters, including M.S.S., Moslem Student Society, 1981,and Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - National Immigration Coalition, Los Angeles, poster and invitation, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Non-Citizen Americans, papers and letters, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - El Obrero Y Sus Derechos, Publicado por El Comité de Servicio de los Amigos, Pasadena, Ca., cartoon pamphlet, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Ocegueda-Chaves, Amalia v. INS, ca. 1973 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Orange County Director of Welfare and Social Services Administration, Dennis Hart appointed, April 6, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Orange County Immigration Coalition, mailing list, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Orange County Report The Economic Impact of Undocumented Immigrants on Public Health Services in Orange County: A Study of Medical Costs, Tax Contributions and Health Needs of Undocumented Immigrants, March 1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Patronato Pro-Defensa de Inmigrantes en Tijuana, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Perez-Lopez, Jóse Jesús and Eugenio Perez-Lopez, v. INS, ca. 1969; and Appeal, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - El Plan Carter, El Bombardeo Como Ciudadanos, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Plight of the Undocumented Aliens in America, paper by the Immigration Coalition, Los Angeles, (11) pages, December 27, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Preliminary Report, Domestic Council Committee on Illegal Aliens, by the Coalición Nacional Pro Leyes Y Practicas Justas de Inmigración, December 1976 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Primer Encuentro de los Trabajadores Industriales, Agrícolas y Pequeños Productores de Caña de Azúcar de América Latina Y del Caribe, March 12, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - The Problem of the Undocumented Worker: A View from the United States, by Dr. Joseph Sommers, UCSD, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Problemas de inmigración, papers and presentations, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Problems of Persons without Immigration Documents in the Central Los Angeles Region, by United Way-Region 5, (25) pages, July 28, 1975;additional papers on tax costs and services of undocumented persons in the Los Angeles area, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Projections for the Creation of `Cedoas', by National Commission on Hispanic Affairs, Spanish and English, 1973? (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Proposals to amend codes and regulations dealing with undocumented workers, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Protection for Immigrants, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Regulations on employment of temporary alien workers, United States Department of Labor, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Repressive Legislation, flyers and brochures, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Rights of Aliens, (7) pages, Southeast Legal Aid Center, Compton, California, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Salinas Rocha, Irma, article Nuestros Indocumentados, from Primera Sección, p. 6, Octubre de 1979 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Rodino and Trade Unions, resolutions and clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Rodino and the United Farm Workers, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Rodino Bill, and other immigration bills, clippings and flyers, 1969-1976 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Rodino Bill, Campaign against, includes Legislative Analysis HR-8713, prepared by C.A.S.A., pamphlets, clippings and flyers, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Rodino Bill, Labor resolutions, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Rodino Bill, petition and flyers, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Rodino Bill, United States Commission on Civil Rights position, August 6, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Rodino Immigration Bill HR-8713, reports and flyers, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Roybal Bill, amendment to Immigration and Nationality Act, April 5, 1977; The Subtle Menace of Legal and Illegal Aliens in Times of Economic Recession, by Cecil E. Johnson, January 24, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Roybal, Congressman Edward, Censure case, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Salida Voluntaria, flyers, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Select Commission on Immigration Policy document, (55) pages, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Select Commission on Immigration Policy Staff Report Abstract of Recommendations to Full Select Commission on Immigration and Refuge Policy, [unpaged], December 15, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Select Commission on Immigration Policy, Staff Report Abstract of Recommendations to Full Select Commission on Immigration and Refuge Policy, [unpaged], December 15, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Simpson-Mazzoli Bill, flyers, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Sindical Bi-Nacional Sobre Problemas de Inmigración, papers and speeches, Tijuana, September 8, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Sisters of St. Francis Dutch Province, contribution of $30,000 to the Western Center for Immigration Studies and the National Committee to Unionize Undocumented Workers, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - La Situación del los Trabajadores Migratorios Indocumentados, Comisión Nacional Asuntos Migratorios para Comisión Ejecutiva del C.C., (15) pages plus appended material, ca. 1980? (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Southern California Association of Governments, Los Angeles, Proposal for a Study to Determine an Estimate of Undocumented Aliens and Undercounted Population in the Scag Region, July 13, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - The Subtle Menace of Legal and Illegal Aliens in Times of Economic Recession, by Cecil E. Johnson, January 24, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Task Force Report, Secretary of Labor Ray Marshall, Report to President Carter on Undocumented Aliens, April 27, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Tax and Visa Cases, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Tuscon, Arizona, El Concilio Manzo, voluntary organization assisting immigrants, 1977, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Tuscon, Arizona, Manzo Area Council, records seizure by federal agents, clippings and legal documents, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - The Unconstitutionality of Legislation Which Prohibited the Employment of Undocumented Immigrants, by Isaias D. Torres, typescript, April 1978 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - The Undocumented Workers, Present and Future, by Dr. Vic Villapando, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Vatican policy on immigrants, 1969, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 13)